Guide to the Nicholas School Master's Projects, 1933-2005 UA.18.01.0003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- 2000 -- Master's Projects, 4 boxes
  - Kubik, Julie A.: Trimethyltin-Induced Injury in the Mouse Hippocampus: Role of Microglia Activation in Neurodegeneration, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Lanteri, Charlotte Anne: Isolation and Partial Characterization of Human Hemoglobin Adducts as a Result of Acrylamide Exposure, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Lauer, Jean: An Analysis of Interagency Cooperation and Partnership in Conservation Planning in Idaho, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Leach, Julie M.: Hydrodiplomacy: Mitigating International Freshwater Conflict in the Mekong River Basin, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Lee, Wan-Hsuan: Selected Agricultural Best Management Practices in the Te-Chi Reservoir Watershed, Taiwan, 2000 (Box 5)
  - LeVine, Michael: Using Computerized Decision Analysis Tools to Model Environmental Litigation, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Lin, Fang-Hsu: Using Microsomal Monooxygenases System of Brown Rats for the Evaluation of Reclaimed Fure-Der-Kung Landfill in Taiwan, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Lipsitch, Joel: Product Deselection: Understanding and Responding to Consumer Pressure to Improve Environmental Performance in the Chemical Industry, 2000 (Box 5)
  - McVeigh, John M.: Standardizing TRI Reporting Practices: A Case Study of the Semiconductor Industry, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Metzger, Jessica M.: Assessing Forest Health Using Tree Crown Measurements, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Moore, Kathleen (Katie): Take Reduction Process Handbook: Improving Marine Mammal Bycatch Management, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Mooreside, Peter Douglas: Integration of Physical Oceanography with Spatio-Temporal Patterns of Stranded Sea Turtles in North Carolina, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Moriya, Takashi: Trends in soil cation-leaching under the Free Air Carbon-dioxide Enrichment (FACE) Experiment, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Myers, Sara E.: Nonpoint Pollution from Animal Sources: Public Health Concerns and Methods for Detection in Recreational Beach Waters, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Nevius, Sherri Corbin: Illegal Dumping in North Carolina: An Assessment and Prevention Guide, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Newbold, Rochelle: A Struggle to Remain Pristine: A Policy Analysis of Local Government in the Bahamas and Its Struggle Between Economic Development and Conservation, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Norenberg, Karen M.: Survival of E. coli in Seawater Due to Growth in Biofilms, 2000 (Box 5)
  - O'Connor, Jennifer M.: Regeneration and Growth of Mahagany (Sweitenia Macrophylla King) in Belize: Implications for Sustainable Management, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Ott, Nicole Christine: The Application of Permeable Reactive Barriers to Inorganic Contaminant Remediation, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Painter, Rusty: Analysis of Parking Impacts on the Trees of Forest Hills Park, Durham, NC, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Park, Robin: Mitigating Coastal Hazards through Property Acquisition – An Analysis of Oceanfront Property in Nags Head, North Carolina, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Paulson, Amy L.: Prioritization of Riparian Buffer Protection and Restoration in the Upper Tar River Basin Using a Geographic Information System, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Rakestraw, Catherine A.: An Evaluation of the Risk-Based Approach to Brownfield Remediation and Development, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Ramacciotti, Francis Christopher: Modeling of Nitrogen Transport and Transformation in Soil at Duke University's Free Air Carbon Exchange Site, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Rangel, Jorge Rivera: Does it pay to be green in the developing world? Participation in a Costa Rican voluntary environmental program and its impact on hotels' competitive advantage, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Rogers, Bradley D.: Using Statistical Indicators to Track Maryland's 'Smart Growth' Agenda, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Schichtel, Heather L.: Spatial Analysis of Seedling Distribution in a Peruvian Rain Forest, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Schick, Robert S.: Spatial Components of Bowhead Whale (Balaena mysticetus) Distribution in the Alaskan Beaufort Sea, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Schnee, Nicholas: Observations on the ISO 14001 Registration System and the Registrar's Role in Encouraging Environmental Performance, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Serrano, Sara Patricia Zurita: Ecosystem Valuation: Concepts, Theories and Empirics, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Shibata, Kazunao: The Reform of the Pollution Levy System in China, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Shipman, Susan J.: Community-Based and Environmentally Responsible Tourism in the Okavango Delta, Botswana, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Simmons, Wendy L.: An Evaluation of the North Carolina Natural heritage Program with Emphasis on the Registry of Natural Areas, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Singh, Sumita: A Changing Southern Landscape: Rapid Land-Cover Changes in North Carolina from 1982-1997, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Snyder, Lorraine A.: Leasing Copiers: Strategy to Reduce Materials Use?, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Soell, Joseph E.: Effective Management Techniques of Fish Communities in a Restored Wetland, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Sortais, Kristen: An Evaluation of Controlled Access in the Georgia Blue Crab Fishery, 2000 (Box 5)
  - TePas, Kristin M.: An Evaluation of the Proposed Re-Introduction of the Bloater (Coregonus hoyi) into Lake Ontario, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Watts, Sarah C.: The Effects of Reduced Flooding Frequency on Species Composition in a Bottomland Hardwood Stand in the Piedmont of North Carolina, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Williams, Mya D.: Nitrogen Deposition as a Causal Agent in Northern Hardwood Forest Decline in the Southern Appalachians, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Wintergreen, James T.: A Hedonic Analysis of Residential Development and Water Quality in the Lake Jeanette Watershed, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Wu, David C.: Ecological and Political Dynamics of Fish Nursery Areas: Marshallberg, NC, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Yang, Jui-Chen: Exploring Diverse Public Preferences for the Nantahala and Pisgah National Forests in North Carolina, 2000 (Box 6)
- 2001 -- Master's Projects, 3 boxes
  - Asano, Koji: People in a Protected Area Evaluating the Socioeconomic Characteristics and Resource Extraction of Fishing Villages on Lake Malawi National Park, Malawi, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Asher, Jacob (Jake) Marcus: The North Carolina Stop Net Fishery: A Case Study of Conflicts Between Fisheries and Bottlenose Dolphins, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Barnas, Katherine A.: The Hurricanes of 1999: A Look at the Effects on Fisheries and Fishers in the Neuse River and Pamlico Sound, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Barnhill, William O. III: A Look Towards Antillean Manatee Conservation n the 21st Century: Evaluating th Progress of the Caribbean Environment Programme's 1995 Regional Management Plan, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Bickel, Kathryn A.: Land Use, Disturbance, and the Spread of Non-Native Plant Species in a Piedmont Forest Ecosystem, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Blake, Laura J.: A Hydrologic Error Analysis of the Warme (Watershed Analysis Risk Management Framework) Model for the Linville River, NC, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Bleckinger, Amy E.: The Monitoring and Management of the Endangered Plant, Sidalcea Oregana Var. Calva (Wenatchee Mountains Checker Mallow), 2001 (Box 6)
  - Bodwell, Jason Michael: Effective Marketing Strategies for Certified Forest Products, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Byers, David J.: Reproductive Behavior and Habitat Regime of the Blue Crab, Callinectes Sapidus: Policy Implications for North Carolina's Most Valuable Fishery, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Byron, Lee Hayes: Public/Private Partnerships in Land Conservation: A Case Study and Comparative Analysis of Local Land Conservation Programs in Florida, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Felipe Carazo: Andringitra National Park (Madagascar): Analysis and Recommendations for an Ecotourism Strategy, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Chang, Roger K.: Stochastic Model to Relate Sediment Transport Characteristics of Hydrological Benchmark Network Sites to Land Characteristics, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Cho, Iihwan: Spatial and Temporal Patterns of Minke Whale (Balaenoptera acutorostrata) Distributions off the East Coast of Korea, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Cooper, Peter W.: Helicobacter sp. in Beaufort Area Waters, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Corridore, Angela: Evaluating the Socioeconomic Impacts of Temporary Shellfishing Closures, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Dennison, Rebecca K.: Environmental Benefits of Pay-As-You-Drive Auto Insurance: Driving Behavior Changes Resulting from an Innovative Billing Method, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Dermer, Phyllis: Making it Work: Enforcement Issues in Marine Protected Areas, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Didier, Joseph (Jay) D.: Market Development Potential for Certified Forest Products, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Dobrzynski, Tanya J. and Elizabeth E. Nicholson: An Evaluation of the Short-Term Social and Economic Impacts of Marine Reserves on User Groups in Key West, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Etnoyer, Peter J.: Marine Protected Area Siting for Coral Reefs in a Large Marine, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Fitzsimmons, Sara Fern: An Assessment of a Program for the Breeding of a Blight-resistant American Chestnut (castanea dentata), 2001 (Box 6)
  - Franks, Rachael J.: Analysis of Harbor Porpoise (Phocoena phocoena) Strandings in North Carolina (1977 - 2000), 2001 (Box 6)
  - Gatewood, M. Melissa: Stakeholder Priorities for Conservation on South Carolina's North Coast, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Haunreiter, Erik S.: Herbivory and Patterns of Tree Recruitment on Land-bridge Islands in Lago Guri, Venezuela, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Herzer, Paul: Design of a Wastewater Treatment Facility for a Brewery Expansion on the Outer Banks of North Carolina, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Hessling, Michael E.: Turf Landscapes Versus Xeriscapes: Analysis of Residential Landscapes in the Las Vegas Valley, Nevada, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Hill, Jason: A Comparative Analysis of Probabilistic Data and Non-Random Water Quality Data in the Savannah River Basin, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Huggler, Matthew C.: An Analysis of External Threats to the National Marine Sanctuary System, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Humphries, W. Richard: Timber Harvest Scheduling: A Practical Comparison of IRR and NPV, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Hutson, Andrew M.: ISO 14001 and the American Automobile Industry in Mexico, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Job, Scott C.: River Basin-Scale Characterization of Riparian Forest Buffers with GIS, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Johnson, Holly S.: Conservation Restrictions on Cape Cod: Improving their Utilization as a Method to Conserve Land, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Johnson, Jeremiah O.: Determination of Ground Water Vulnerability of Karst Terrane within Augusta County, Virginia Using a Gis-Based Drastic Model, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Kafalenos, Robert S.: Relicensing Nuclear Power Plants Implications for Nuclear Wastes and Carbon Dioxide Emissions, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Karas, Cassie: Case Study: Motivating Decision Criteria to Implement a Paper Recycling Program within a Facility, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Kochi, Ikuho: A Meta Analysis of the Value of a Statistical Life for Environmental Policy Analysis, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Kohler, Keisha W.: Effects of In Situ Oxidation with Potassium Permanganate on Subsurface Microbial Activity, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Koska, Andrea C.: Aquadale, NC: A Community Suffering From the Effects of Hazardous Waste?, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Kunz, July: The Remediation of Hunters Point Annex Superfund Site San Francisco, California, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Kwon, Ho-young: An Environmental Impact Assessment Saemangeum Tidal Flats Development Project in South Korea: A Reanalysis, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Lafrenz, Ryan R.: Approaches to Maintaining and Abandoning Forest Roads in the Northwest Region of the United States, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Lin, Jeff: A Comparison of HGM Variables and Wetland Decomposition Rates in the Nanticoke River Watershed, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Lindow, Emily R.: The Use of Purchase of Development Rights for Coastal Open Space Protection: A Case Study on Edisto Island, South Carolina, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Maruyama, Aimee Lunde: Brownfield Redevelopment in Ohio: An Analysis of the Voluntary Action Program, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Medori, Amanda: A Model for Assessing Watershed Integrity and Conservation Value to Supplement a Wildlands Network Design for the Chesapeake Bay Basin, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Mizutani, Yukiko: Function and Effectiveness of the Extractive Reserve Model in the Brazilian Amazon: Can it be a Solution for Sustainable Development? 2001 (Box 19)
  - Morgan, Leigh E.: Patterns of Damage Caused by Feral Swine (Sus scrofa) in the Big thicket National Preserve, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Muller, Lori Beth: Industrial Used Oil Management: A Case Study International Paper Bucksport, Maine Mill, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Nash, Harriet L.: The Impact of Ray Feeding on Spatial Ecology of Intertidal Sand Flats, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Norwood, Carla M.: Changes in Land Use and Water Quality in the Yadkin River Basin, 1951 - 2000, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Nygaard, Anna C.: Woody-Plant Diversity within Forests of the Southeastern United States, 2001 (Box 7)
  - O'Connell, Jeffery Scott: Integration of Design for the Environment (DfE) Programs in the Electronics Industry, 2001 (Box 7)
  - O'Connor, Timothy Joseph: Analysis of Fine Particulate Matter Enhancement at a North Carolina swine Lagoon, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Ogata, Hiroki: Exposure Assessments for Contaminated Soil Dust in Japan, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Orphanides, Christopher: Development of an Estuarine Biotic Integrity Index (EBI) Based on Fish Communities in Narragansett Bay: Implications for Fish Habitat, Management, and Ecosystem Health, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Ozarski, Jill N.: Land Trusts & Public Capacity-Building Grants: A Statistical Model of Local Land Trust Effectiveness, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Park, Daniel S.: Beach Nourishment in Southern California: A Case Study of the San Diego Regional Beach Sand Project, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Park, Haewon: The Biogeochemical Cycling of Boron, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Paukovits, Jason M.: Smart Growth Planning in Eastern Massachusetts, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Peet, Katherine: Environmental Impacts on the Hatching Success of Loggerhead Sea Turtle (Caretta caretta) Nests on Keewaydin Island, Florida, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Peterson, Heather A.: Whale Behavioral Responses and Human Perceptions: An Assessment of Humpback Whales (Megaptera novaeangliae) and Vessel Activity Near Juneau, Alaska, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Philipp, Matthew: Little and Shark Harbors Conservation and Land Use Plan, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Ramach, Sean: A 3D Spatial Ecology Study of Blue Crabs, Callinectes sapidus, in a High Salinity Embayment, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Rape, Lindsay R.: Southeast Florida Sea Turtle Conservation: A Draft Plan for Developed Nesting Beaches, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Rogers, Donna P.: Developing an Environmental Education Resource: The Video "Understanding Air Toxics", 2001 (Box 7)
  - Shawl, Amber: Closing the Cycle: Captive Breeding for the Gastropod Strombus, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Shumate, Christina: Riparian Corridor Conservation Plan for Contentnea Creek, North Carolina, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Shwom, Rachael L.: Communicating Scientific Uncertainty: A Case Study of Climate Change Scientists' Testimonies Before Congress, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Smith, James D.: Characterization of the Superoxide Dismutase Expression in Two Populations of Fundulus heteroclitus, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Smith, Nathan: Ranking Subbasins of the B. Everett Jordan Lake Watershet for Sediment Erosion Potential, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Staten, Shane C.: Seed Bank Study for Enhancement of the Williamson River Delta Preserve Wetland Restoration Project Near Klamath Falls, Oregon, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Stephens, Katherine M.: A Landscape Analysis of the Effectiveness of Agricultural Best Management Practices on a Coastal North Carolina Estuary, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Suwa, Makoto: Reconstruction of the Late Holocene Palcoenvironment around Laguna Umayo, Peru Using Chemical and Isotopic Analyses of a Lake Sediment Core, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Tang, Yu-Ting: Toxicity Identification and Evaluation of the Elizabeth River, VA, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Taylor, John A.: The Westhampton Dunes Lawsuit: A Case Study of Human Induced Coastal Erosion, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Timyan, Joel C.: Status and Conservation of Attalea Crassispatha (Mart.) Burret, A Rare and Endemic Palm of Haiti, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Tomasi, Peter A.: Unraveling the Daubert Puzzle: Causation in Environmental Toxic Tort Litigation, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Torres, Leigh G.: Improving Management of Overlapping Bottlenose Dolphin Ecotypes through Spatial Analysis and Genetics, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Treutelaar, Jennifer: Business Plan for Lassen Volcanic National Park, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Turley, Evie: The Effects of Wetland Restoration on Water Quality: A Baseline Assessment of Water Quality Indices in Sandy Creek Durham, North Carolina, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Vallianos, Kostoula: The Palmetto Peartree Preserve Land Use Plan: Using GIS to Optimize for Multiple and Conflicting Objectives, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Van Exem, Oliver L.: Chemometric Exploration of Pesticide Retention in Two NC Piedmont Soils, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Vignola, Mark J.: Green Fluorescent Protein: When Science Meets Business (Fluorescence of the Temperate Facultatively Symbiotic Coral Oculina arbuscula Suggests the Presence of Green Fluorescent Proteins), 2001 (Box 8)
  - Vuturo, Christopher M.: Application of National Water Quality Database and GIS to Risk Assessment: Organic Carbons and Metals, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Waeckerlin, Eric: Using Conservation Leases to Protect Wyoming Ranchland, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Wang, Ting-Jieh: Responsibilities of a Newly Industrialized Country: A Case Study of Taiwan's Reactions Toward International Environmental Accords, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Webb, Laura: A New Frontier for Environmental Education: The Development and Evaluation of an Air Quality Curriculum for Churches, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Wilson, Joanna D.: Assessing Environmental Stewardship at Duke University, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Wong, Carissa M.: Species Regeneration Response to Clearing Size: A Swietenia Macrophylla King Harvested Forest in Northern Belize, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Yoda, Emi: Measuring the Economic Benefits of Coral Reefs to Small-Scale Fishers: A Case Study in North Sulawesi, Indonesia, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Zurawski, Carol A.: Decision Analysis: A Feasible Tool for Improving Species Management Decisions?, 2001 (Box 8)
- 2002 -- Master's Projects, 4 boxes
  - Atachley, Jennifer C.: Comprehensive Assessment of Manatee (Trichechus manatus latirostris) Non-Wintering Habitat in Northwest Florida, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Auer, Donald Patrick: A Species Habitat Model for the Cerulean Warbler in Western North Carolina for Use in the Important Bird Area Program, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Batch, Lawrence F.: Quantification of Damage to Virus DNA from Ultraviolet (UV) Exposure, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Bhalla, Abhas: Socially Responsible Investing and Corporate Social Responsibility A Case Study - The Energy Big Five, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Bird, Christina: South Carolina Oyster Restoration and Enhancement (SCORE) Community-Based Program: A Manual for Volunteers and Volunteer Coordinators, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Block, Jennifer: Two Paradigms of EPR in the Carpet Industry/A Comparison of Take-Back and Recycling Initiatives in the United States and Europe, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Bodien, Scott Michael: A Case Study Examining the Landscape Management System with Duke Forest Permanent Sample Plot Data, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Brandt, Sara: The Effect of Increased Atmospheric CO2 Concentrations on Forest Canopy Interception and Throughfall Chemistry, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Canny, David S.: Ecological Connectivity: The Case for Reserve Networks in Marine Environments, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Castellan, Allison: Developing a NPDES Phase II Storm Water Model Permit for Coastal North Carolina Communities, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Chambers, Noelle: Site Conservation Planning in The Cedars, Virginia: Optimizing Multiple Conservation Goals in the Aquatic, Terrestrial, and Subterranean Systems, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Cheruvettolil, Kochukoshy: Online Environmental Activism (Methodological Analysis of the Roadless Areas Campaign), 2002 (Box 9)
  - Childs, Tara: A Prioritization for Preservation of Millponds in Eastern North Carolina, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Chow, Jeffery: Sustainable Mahogany Management: Regeneration within Anthropogenic Canopy Gaps in the Subtropical Moist Forests of Belize, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Cluse, Wendy Margaret: Boat Activity and Sea Turtle Mortality: Exploring the Severity of the Problem in North Carolina Waters, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Darling, Susan: The Effect of Secondary Treatment on Water Quality In Boston Harbor, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Dietzel, Charles: A Spatial Model of Land Use/Land Cover Change: Rockbridge County (VA), 2002 (Box 9)
  - Dixon, Sarah: Analysis of Landuse Change in the Trent River Watershed - A Focus on the Rise of Hog Farming, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Escobar, Alejandro: Cost and Loadings Models for Propose Effluent Guidelines to the Aquaculture Industry: Flow Through Systems, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Fahey, Colleen: Testing a Short-Cut for Managing Species with Minimal Demographic Data, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Fisher, Heather L.: A Benefit-Cost Analysis of Natural Drainage for Residential Developments: A Case Study of Lenoir County, NC, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Foster, Ellery: Greening the Christian Church: An Institutional Analysis, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Frangione, Christopher S.: Power Generator Asset Development Strategies: Emissions Regulations and the Variable Cost of Power, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Fujinuma, Miwa: Investigation of Financial Loss in the Shrimp Industry in the Philippines, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Galik, Christopher S.: The Role of Cites Appendix III in Monitoring the Trade of Brazilian Bigleaf Mahogany, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Gannon, Sarah E.: The Status of the Central American Squirrel Monkey (Saimiri oerstedi citrinellus) in Costa Rica, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Gardner, Autumn Daune: A Survey of Perspectives Regarding Personal Watercraft Use on Lake Marion in South Carolina, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Gehman, Seth D.: Whitetail Deer Browse on Loblolly Pine Seedlings in the Duke Forest: Options for Management, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Gindre, Sarah: Assessing the Application of Integrated Coastal Management Principles: A Case Study of Spain, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Hagedorn, Sarah C.: Depredation by Bottlenose Dolphins on Gill Nets in Dare County, North Carolina, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Hanily, George: Residual Effects of Arsenic Based Agrochemicals on a South Carolina Piedmont Soil, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Harkless, Kelly: Evaluation of Ballast Water Resolution and Accuracy of Ballast Water Reporting in Washington State Waters, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Harper, Craig W.: Southwestern Connections: Using Graph Theory to Assess Landscape Connectivity for Mountain Lions and Mexican Spotted Owls, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Harris, Adrienne L.: Addressing Global Scale Environmental Issues: Developing an International Convention for the Control of Ballast Water, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Himes, Amber Hintz: Small-Scale Sicilian Artisanal Fisheries: Opinions of Artisanal Fishers and Socio-Cultural Effects of Marine Protected Areas, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Hooker, Brian R.: Community-Integrated GIS in the Bay of Fundy Groundfishery, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Horner, Amy L.: Environmental Justice in Local Land Use Planning: Durham City/County: A Case Study, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Hoshino, Eriko: Marine Turtle Ecology in Relation to Pelagic Longline Bycatch and Squid Distribution, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Hulme, John R.: EPA's Strategic Regulation of Western Coalbed Natural Gas Development, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Huang Fu, Wei-Chun: Chlorpyrifos (CPF) Activated Gene Transcription by Oxidative Stress, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Hummel, Jason A.: Market Development for Hybrid Automobiles in the United States, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Humphrey, Genesis M.: Identifying the Barriers to Forest Recovery in an Abandoned Pasture in Costa Rica, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Hwang, Wendy W.: Sorption of Rhodamine WT (RWT) Isomers in Southeastern Ultisols: Implications for Tracing 2, 4-dichlorophenoxyacetic acid (2, 4-D), 2002 (Box 9)
  - Jung, Goosun: Germany's Environmental Standards and Requirements for Textile Sector and Their Positive Impacts On China, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Kern, Stephanie L.: The Application of Water Purification Techniques to Lake Norman Water as a Substitute for Ceriodaphnia dubia Culture Media, 2002 (Box 9)